# **PAULINE P. NARVAS**

Leeds, UK | pauline@paulinenarvas.com | linkedin.com/in/pnarvas | paulinenarvas.com

### **PROFILE**

Equipped with strong technical and communication skills built from 2 years on a competitive graduate scheme, 3 years as a remote web developer and 4 years developing communities. With self-development at the centre of my character, I'm continuously eager to fill gaps in my technical knowledge and skills to be the best engineer that I can be. I recently became Amazon Web Services (AWS) Certified with the Cloud Practitioner (CCP) certification! I've been listed on Code First: Girls' Top 25 under 30 in tech, Northern Power Women's Future List and J.P. Morgan's x The Tab Future 100 List.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Digital Engineering Graduate, BT | Sept 2018 - Present

Two year graduate scheme, four six month rotations within BT Consumer Digital.

#### Rotation 4 - Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) | March 2020 - Present

- Contributed to development of the new SRE team, helping drive the team's goals and long-term vision and advocating the value that the team has within BT Consumer division and wider BT Group.
- Contributed to the development of our cloud computing standards striving for operational excellence across BT Group. Focusing on optimizing cost, performance, reliability and security.
- Using serverless technology such as Lambda and SNS for automation of manual tasks, creating reliable processes.

### Rotation 3 - Platform Services | Sept 2019 - March 2020

- Standardised BT Consumer Digital's delivery pipeline for cloud infrastructure provisioning and development CI/CD workflows, promoting a consistent approach on our infrastructure.
- Assisted other engineering teams integrations with our CI/CD e.g. Jenkins
- Advocated Platform Services and the power of our tools to speed up releases into production
- Tech includes: AWS, Terraform, Packer, Vault, Consul, Linux, Python, Ansible, k8s, Docker, Jenkins, Unix

#### Key achievements:

- Led the Single Sign On (SSO) project delivery and implementation for Slack with Jenkins and Shibboleth for BT Enterprise, using Terraform. Transforming the way colleagues communicate with each other.
- Automated a long process of creating static websites. Built a self-serve service that allows colleagues to spin up
  their own static website within minutes using AWS Route 53, S3, Terraform and Jenkins. This improved the speed
  of smaller project deliveries.

### Rotation 2 - MyEE Web (Development) | March 2019 - Sept 2019

- Worked with remote developers in Belarus and India, using Scrum
- Contributed to several scheduled production releases for MyEE Web
- Developed Proof of Concepts that improved our current approach on automation and looked at ways to improve our current tech stack
- Tech includes: HTML, CSS/SCSS, Javascript, Java, git

#### Key achievements:

- Built new UI features including development on the Roaming and Add-ons page. Improving the user experience for the 10 million customers who are registered on MyEE.
- Led in prioritising technical debt through refactoring projects, which helped keep our large codebase clean.

### Rotation 1 - Digital Architecture | Sept 2018 - March 2019

Worked with key stakeholders from impacted squads to gather key requirements of propositions

- Produced impact assessments with new propositions to present at the Digital IA forum
- Identified ways we can improve our digital tools, technology and architecture

**Key achievement:** Part of the team that looked at simplifying enterprise tooling strategy to better our ways of working. This led to the implementation of Slack which is now used as the primary internal communication tool across Digital.

#### Other notable contributions:

- Featured in the BT rebrand campaign Beyond Limits
- Featured in The Yorkshire Post, The Daily Mirror, The Sheffield Star to share my career journey
- Organised a BT International Women's Day event in our Leeds office, bringing together women from the local community.
- Organised a "Techy Tea party" with Leeds Library to help grow essential digital skills for the general public.
- Organised a BT Hack Day with the University of Leeds to promote BT's new technical direction and inspire innovation in students.

### Remote Web Developer, The University of Sheffield | Nov 2017 - May 2020

- Developed an independent research-focused website for PhD students and research fellows in the Department of Civil and Structural Engineering.
- Continuous improvement with new features, site optimisation and general maintenance of the website that continues to engage researchers internationally.

**Key achievement:** Implemented Wordpress for research fellows to share their research and contributions in the field, improving visibility of their work across higher education.

#### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

- 2016 2019: Organiser, Ambassador and Lead Instructor, Code First: Girls
- 2017 2018: Enterprise Intern, The University of Sheffield Enterprise (USE)
- 2017 2018: HackMed Hackathon Organiser, MedTech Sheffield
- 2016 2017: Communications and External Engagement Assistant Intern, The University of Sheffield

### **SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS**

- Amazon Web Services Qualified: AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (CCP)
- Web Development: HTML, CSS/SASS, Javascript, jquery, React, Nextjs, PHP, Wordpress
- DevOps: Jenkins, Terraform, Packer, Ansible, Python, Docker
- **Engagement optimisation:** building online presence on social media and improving SEO. My personal blog has grown from 127 unique visitors in 2015 to 5, 471 in 2019.
- **Confident public speaker:** Most notably as a keynote speaker at GitHub Field Day in 2017, expert speaker at "Grow from Your STEM" Gov event in 2018, panelist at DevOps Leeds in 2019 and BT Group's IWD event in 2020.
- Passionate community builder: brought together different tech communities including Code First: Girls, HackSheffield and MedTech at Sheffield University, and leading on various Women in Tech initiatives.

#### **EDUCATION**

The University of Sheffield | 2014 - 2018

BSc (Hons) Biomedical Sciences with Employment Experience

Tapton School | 2008 - 2014

3 A Levels: Biology, Chemistry and Sociology 12 A\*-C GCSEs including Maths, English and Triple Science

## **REFERENCES**

Available upon request